# **Ben Garlock**

New York, NY | 646-241-6885 | ben.garlock@gmail.com | Github | Blog | LinkedIn | Portfolio

#### **SOLUTIONS ENGINEER**

A Solutions Engineer and Software Developer with a strong emphasis on driving client value using technology and data. Over fifteen years of experience in troubleshooting complex technical issues in high pressure environments. Patient, organized, and professional.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, Postgres, HTML5, CSS, Javascript, React, Redux, Python, Django, Github, API, Pandas, DNS, Firewall Management, Apache, TCP/IP, Virtualization, MacOS, Windows, Linux

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

**FluffyTail** - Adoption resource for finding and locating rescue pets.

Github | LiveSite - Ruby on Rails | PostgreSQL

- Implemented data gathering from live pet adoption APIs for real time results.
- Constructed generalized single-search module for easy query of breed, species, or pet name.
- Harnessed Bootstrap 4 CSS for fast and efficient deployment of site design.

**StarIron** - Game for researching an astrological sign.

Github | LiveSite - JavaScript | Rails

- Leverages Vanilla JavaScript to generate randomized CSS "stars" that dynamically change.
- Optimized user experience with asynchronous CRUD actions for persisting and modifying user content.
- Features data collection across multiple public APIs.

**TableHost -** Restaurant reservation and guest management system.

Github | LiveSite - React | Rails | Django

- Fully operational restaurant reservation system which includes booking reservations, seating guests, and guest record management.
- Provides data analytics and performance metrics to allow restaurants to better manage their operations.
- Backend featuring both Rails and Django based API's.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Sr. Account Manager - OpenTable/Kayak - New York, NY

3/2017 - 5/2020

- Directly responsible for maintaining 300+ elite, high-value OpenTable restaurant partnerships.
- Coordinated with software development teams to provide product feedback, deploy new features, and conduct production tests.
- Utilized data and analytical tools to assist OpenTable partners in optimizing best practices and use of the OpenTable platform including marketing, business development products, and inventory utilization.
- Lead partner's system conversion efforts from a legacy system built on client-server architecture to a cloud-based technology product.

## Sr. Field Technician - OpenTable - Chicago, IL

4/2007 - 3/2017

- Deployed the OpenTable reservation and guest management system to 2000+ restaurant customers across North America including large-scale hotels, casinos, resorts, and enterprise restaurant groups.
- Provided in-person consultations with restaurant staff to optimize best practices and use of the OpenTable platform.

### Sr. Customer Support Technician - OpenTable - San Francisco, CA

3/2004 - 4/2007

- Provided technical and training support to 15,000+ domestic and international OpenTable restaurant customers.
- Managed special project teams to maintain data security, network health, and application patching.
- Resolved high-level service outage issues in high pressure environments.

### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** 

June 2020 - October 2020 Full Stack Web Development. Ruby on Rails, React, JavaScript **DeVry University** 

June 2001 - March 2004

Computer Network Administration.

Bachelor of Science - 127 credits completed